<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>concept on</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/tags/concept/</link><description>Recent content in concept on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://glossary.airbyte.com/tags/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Engineering Concepts</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/data-engineering-concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/data-engineering-concepts/</guid><description>Some core concepts we are going to explore:
Data Warehouse vs Data Lake vs Data Lakehouse Storage Layer vs Data Lake File Format vs Data Lake Table Format Data Catalog Modern Data Stack vs Open Data Stack Data Engineering Lifecycle ELT vs ETL vs EtLT Functional Data Engineering vs Software-Defined Assets Metrics Layer vs Semantic Warehouse vs Data Virtualization Metrics, Key Performance Indicator (KPI) Push-Downs vs Rollup Data Modeling vs Dimensional Modeling Data Contract OLAP vs OLTP MapReduce and Apache Hadoop Declarative vs Imperative Notebooks See also What is Data Engineering.</description></item><item><title>Data Engineering Guides</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/data-engineering-guides/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/data-engineering-guides/</guid><description>Some Data Engineering Guides that will help you learn data engineering:
Data Quality How to handle [[term/data quality]] issues by detecting, understanding, fixing, and reduce Data Lake / Lakehouse Guide The what &amp;amp; why of a Data Lake Differences between Lakehouse &amp;amp; Data Warehouse Components of a data lake Storage Layer Data Lake File Format Data Lake Table Format with Apache Parquet, Apache Iceberg, and Apache Hudi Trends in the market We answer questions such as: How to build an open-source data lake offloading data for analytics?</description></item><item><title>What is EtLT?</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/etlt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/etlt/</guid><description>EtLT refers to Extract, “tweak”, Load, Transform, and can be thought of an extension to the ELT approach to data integration.</description></item><item><title>What is semi-structured data?</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/semi-structured-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/semi-structured-data/</guid><description>Semi-structured data is data that lacks a rigid structure and that does not conform directly to a data model, but that has tags, metadata, or elements that describe the data.</description></item><item><title>What is structured data?</title><link>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/structured-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glossary.airbyte.com/term/structured-data/</guid><description>Structured data refers to data that has been formatted into a well-defined schema. An example would be data that is stored with precisely defined columns in a relational database or excel spreadsheet.</description></item></channel></rss>